Guide to the Council of Masters, Yale University, Meeting Minutes
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Council of Masters, Yale University, meeting minutes
1932-2005
RU 299
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
20
The records consist of minutes and associated files of the monthly Yale Council of Masters meetings.
Yale University. Council of Masters
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-A (YRG 13-A), Records of the Yale Council of Masters.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Office of the Council of Masters, 1987-2005.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Associated Materials
Records of the Council of Masters (RU 295).
Arrangement
The minutes are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
The Council of Masters was established in 1932, the year the first masters were appointed. The Council makes recommendations to the University President in matters of policy concerning the residential colleges. It also serves as the committee of control in the affairs concerning two or more residential colleges. The Council consists of the masters of the residential colleges. Ex officio members include the University President, Provost Dean of Yale College, Associate Dean of Yale College and Associate Dean for Student Affairs.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes and associated files of the monthly Yale Council of Masters meetings.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Berkeley College (Yale University); Branford College (Yale University); Calhoun College (Yale University); Davenport College (Yale University); Ezra Stiles College (Yale University); Jonathan Edwards College (Yale University); Morse College (Yale University); Pierson College (Yale University); Saybrook College (Yale University); Silliman College (Yale University); Timothy Dwight College (Yale University); Trumbull College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University. Council of Masters
- Council of Masters meeting minutes, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The records contain minutes and material related to the monthly Council of Masters meetings, 1932-2005. Most records from 1932-1992 include associated meeting files, but records from 1993-2005 contain only minutes and the semiannual student census summaries. Associated files may include votes and agreements, memoranda, correspondence with Yale and New Haven administrators, meeting agendas, and requests for Fellows appointments.
  The main content of the minutes themselves concerns the naming and allocation of Fellows to the residential colleges. Other matters mentioned in the minutes include the residential college libraries; visiting hours for women (pre-1969); the coat and tie rule in dining halls; policies for students returning from war; and distribution of Council of Masters funds to student organizations.
  Indices to the meeting minutes for the years 1935-1965 can be found in Box 1. The bound volumes for the years 1932-1943 also contain indices.
  - Indices to meeting minutes, 1935-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 17)
  - Meeting minutes and files
    - 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 18 - 96)
    - 1937-1942 (Box 3, Folder 97 - 158)
    - 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 159 - 211)
    - 1945-1948 (Box 5, Folder 212 - 248)
    - 1948-1950 (Box 6, Folder 249 - 281)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 282 - 310)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 8, Folder 311 - 348)
    - 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 349 - 383)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 10, Folder 384 - 422)
    - 1957-1960 (Box 11, Folder 423 - 470)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 12, Folder 471 - 507)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 13, Folder 508 - 537)
    - 1967 (Box 14, Folder 538 - 555)
    - 1968 (Box 15, Folder 556 - 573)
    - 1969 (Box 16, Folder 574 - 588)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 589 - 605)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 18, Folder 606 - 627)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 628 - 645)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 646 - 665)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 666 - 685)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 686 - 709)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 710 - 732)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 733 - 751)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 752 - 772)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 773 - 792)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2017 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 793 - 814)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2019 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 815 - 832)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2020 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 833 - 854)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2021 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1985-1987 (Box 30, Folder 855 - 876)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2023 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1987-1988 (Box 31, Folder 877 - 892)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2024 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1988 (Box 32, Folder 893 - 908)
    - 1989 (Box 33, Folder 909 - 924)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2025 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1990 (Box 34, Folder 925 - 942)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2026 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1991-1992 (Box 35, Folder 943 - 964)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2028 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1992-1995 (Box 36, Folder 965 - 1001)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 20316 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 1996-2000 (Box 37, Folder 1002 - 1047)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2036 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - 2001-present [2005] (Box 38)
      Minutes are restricted until January 1, 2041 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Bound volumes
    - Volumes 1-4, 1932-1937 (Box 39)
    - Volumes 5-10, 1937-1943 (Box 40)